So we are going to make sure to set up a budget and an alarm for that budget for this course in order for us to not to spend any money or too much money.
So therefore we need to go into the billing console so you can click on the top right of your screen and click on billing and cost management.
So as you can see here I get a lot of access denied. This is because I'm logged in as an IM user, Stefan, for my accounts.
And I had administrator access but even though I have administrator access I cannot access my billing data.
So to fix this you can go into your root accounts. So here I mean my root account as you can see it just says the name of my account. It doesn't say I'm user and then you click on it and you go to accounts.
So from accounts you're going to scroll down and then scrolling down you will find the IM user and roll access to billing information.
And as you can see right now it is deactivated so we need to just activate IM access and this will allow I'm users to access the billing information if they are administrators.
So back into my billing console now and I refresh this page and I refresh again and you can take a bit of time as you can see now I see my data.
So except this for the forecast because there is a data and available exception so insufficient amount of historical data except for this we can see all my cost information in here.
So now let me show you what a billing page looks like for the account that I'm actually using and have some costs.
So as we can see we get some information around the month todays cost we get the total forecast month for the current month and so on and last month total cost.
So from this we can get a few information such as the cost breakdown by month so this is when you start seeing some cost and then we can have a look at bills.
So if you look at bills say you have any cost for this tutorial for this course that's going to December 2023 so you will find at the bottom of it charges by service.
And so you'll see the number of active services right now of 28 and for example if I look at the elastic compute cloud so easy to I see I have 43 dollars of cost in EU Ireland.
And it turns out that here is the breakdown of my cost so there is some Amazon elastic complete not gateway which is costing me 35 dollars and there is some EBS cost there is some elastic IP cost and so on.
So when you go into bills go to the month you're interested in so and then scroll down to get charged by service where you're going to get a lot of information around how every service is being used and how you are build for service which will allow you to break down your bill very easily.
So you can go into free tier on the left hand side so it was does have a free tier and you're going to be able to see the current usage and the forecast usage as well as against what the feature is and then you will see whether or not you're going to pass the feature usage so if you do pass it as a forecast it goes into the red then you are going to be build so make sure you turn off anything that is turned on and potentially costing you money so this is a very very helpful dashboard.
Okay so now let's go ahead and set up a budget so on the left hand side you click on budgets and here you can create a budget that will alert you whenever you reach your thresholds.
So let's create a budget and we're going to use a template simplified and the first one is going to be a zero spend budget so as soon as we reach.
And then you can also use another template for a monthly cost budget and here we say okay we want to have a monthly cost budget of.
And say hey I want to spend no more than $10 per month on this course and then the email recipients are going to be against a final example.
And by the way if you follow this course closely you should not spend any dollars I say you when things can cost you money.
But if you're careful you should not spend any money regardless it's still good to set up a budget just to make sure in case you do mistakes that you don't have a big bill coming to your way.
So now for this $10 budget i'm actually going to reach an email when my actual spend reaches 85% and my when my actual spend is going to reach 100% and if my forecasted spend is expected to also reach 100% so very helpful like have three emails I can receive from this.
So we can create this budget, so you can see, well my zero spend budget has already been exceeded because well I've spent some money this month so i'm getting an email right away at this address.
So with these budgets and access to the free cheer on the left hand side to explore as well as accessing you bills breakdown on the left hand side, you should be able to debug any kind of costing issue and billing issue you have on this course and this is a skill.
We're going to be necessary for you when using AWS all right so that's it for this lecture I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.